bigbustours.com 2018-09-08

# Privacy Policy - International | English

**Privacy Policy**

**Please read this privacy policy carefully.** Respecting the privacy rights of our customers is very important to us. We are committed to complying with the Data Protection Act 1998 and, when it comes into force, the General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679. This privacy policy explains how we collect, store and use personal data about you when you visit our website - [www.bigbustours.com](http://eng.bigbustours.com/), and our mobile, tablet and other applications (our " **Sites"** ). This policy applies to all our Sites regardless of how they are made available to you or accessed by you.

Please read this privacy policy carefully before you start using our Sites, as this policy will apply to your use of our Sites

By accessing, browsing and using our Sites, you confirm that you accept this privacy policy. If you do not want your data to be used as set out in this privacy policy, you should not use our Sites. However, you do not have to consent to any of our marketing in order to use our Sites or receive our products. If you have consented to direct marketing but have subsequently changed your mind, please opt out

Your use of our Sites, including any orders you place, is governed by our Terms and Conditions and our Cookie Policy. Please take the time to read these, as they include important terms which apply to you.

**WHO ARE WE?**

The data controller of our Sites is Big Bus Tours LTD, 110 Buckingham Palace Road, London. If you have any questions about how we treat your personal data, please contact the Data Protection Officer at Big Bus Tours via email to [privacy@bigbustours.com](mailto:privacy@bigbustours.com)

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND WHY DO WE COLLECT IT?**

When you visit our Sites, we may collect:

Information such as your computer’s IP address, browser type and version and anonymous information collected from cookies when you are browsing our Sites. We collect this information to help us understand how to improve our services and our Sites and to ensure that the content on our Sites is presented to you in an effective manner. We have a legitimate business interest for this processing: to ensure that our Site is operating effectively and to provide you with a great service;

Personal information such as your name, address, telephone number and email address as provided by you when you register to Big Bus Tours or place an order with us and enter your payment card details. We collect this information for the following reasons:

\- To process your order. We engage third party processors to process the payment of your order online. We collect this information to perform a contract with you and, if you fail to give us the information that we request, then you may not be able to place an order via our Sites. If you consent to them doing so, the third party processors may store your payment card details to speed up your transaction time.

\- For product development (for example, call backs for feedback on new products), for statistical, market research, testing and survey purposes, to notify you about changes to our Sites or our services. We have a legitimate business interest to collect this information: to continue to improve the services we provide to you;

\- To ensure you receive marketing and offers that are of most interest and relevance to you. To help us achieve this, we may share your data with third party analytics companies to understand your purchasing options. We have a legitimate business interest to collect this information: to get to know your preferences and to personalise our offers to you to improve the marketing you receive from us.

**DIRECT MARKETING: YOUR CONSENT MATTERS**

What have I consented to do?

We will not send direct marketing messages to you unless you have opted-in to our marketing. If you have opted-in, this means that we may contact you via your chosen media (such as SMS, email or mail):

\- with offers about our products;

\- to deliver relevant, tailored advertising to you with information about products or services we feel may interest you.

Can I withdraw my consent?

You are always free to opt-in to our marketing and you are always free to opt-out at any time; this will never have an impact on our commitment to provide you with great service and a quality product. Once you have unsubscribed from marketing messages , we will stop sending you marketing messages as soon as possible but in any event, will do so no later than 30 days from your request to withdraw consent.

How long do you keep my consent?

For all contacts already opted-in to our communications, we will assume you want us to keep in touch until the point you have voluntarily opted out.

Updating your consent

Our database will automatically remove you from our communications once unsubscribed. If you are previously opted in from a historical purchase, but decide you do not want to be opted-in on your next purchase - when presented with the opt-in box, if you choose not to receive marketing communication from us on some or all media, we will update our/your records accordingly.

**WHO DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION WITH?**

We may share your personal information with a purchaser or a potential purchaser of our business. We have a legitimate business interest to do this: to assist with the sale or potential sale of our business.

We may also share your information with data matching, data analysis or direct marketing companies to perform services on our behalf (such as, for example, Google, Facebook and Instagram) who will only be permitted to use your personal information for the purpose of performing that particular function strictly in accordance with our instructions and not for any other purpose. Please see “What information do we collect and why do we collect it?” above for further information.

In some circumstances, we may have to disclose your personal information by law, because a court or the police or other legal or regulatory enforcement agency has asked us for it.

We require all third parties that we work with to treat your personal information as confidential and to fully comply with all applicable data protection and consumer legislation.

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA") pursuant to: (a) the model clauses published by the European pursuant to Commission Decision C(2010) 593 Standard Contractual Clauses (Processors); or (b) where we transfer or store personal data in the United States, the US Privacy Shield Regime. It may also be processed by selected third parties operating outside the EEA engaged in, for example, the processing of your payment details. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to our Sites and any transmission is at your own risk.

Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and corporate policies to safeguard and secure the information we receive.

**HOW TO GET COPIES OF OR AMEND THE INFORMATION WE HAVE COLLECTED**

You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. If you would like a copy of the information held on you, please contact us at [privacy@bigbustours.com](mailto:privacy@bigbustours.com) or by mail to Data Protection Officer, Big Bus Tours, 110 Buckingham Palace Road, London, SW1W 9SA

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us or email us and we will correct or update any information as soon as possible.

**LINKING**

We may link to other websites which are not within our control. Once you have left our Sites, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**LOCATION BASED SERVICES**

**Location Based Service Code of Conduct**

We use Location Based Services (LBS) to understand traffic patterns in venues (our fleet of buses). The location data we capture helps us to understand venues (our fleet of buses), such as how long customers are onboard and how they generally move around tour routes, enhancing operational efficiency and improving user experience.

If you would like to find out more about the data we collect through Mobile Location Analytics MLA, take a look at our solution providers [location analytics policy](https://purple.ai/location-analytics-policy/), alternatively you can [opt out of location analytics](https://purple.ai/location-analytics-optout/)

**Rights of access**

In accordance with your rights under the DPA, you are entitled to request a copy of any personal data that we hold about you (or request a description of such data). To obtain a copy of your data, please contact us using the contact details set out below. We will be entitled to charge a fee of up to £10 for dealing with this request.

You may also ask for any inaccurate information that we hold about you to be corrected or deleted, by contacting us as set out below.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we make to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

Last updated May 2018
